<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
  contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
  this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
  The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
  (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
  the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">

<document>
  <header>
    <title>Chukwa: Architecture and Design</title>
  </header>
  <body>
	  <section><title>Introduction</title>
	   	<p>
  	  Log processing was one of the original purposes of MapReduce. Unfortunately,
  	  using Hadoop for MapReduce processing of logs is somewhat troublesome. 
  	  Logs are generated incrementally across many machines, but Hadoop MapReduce
  	  works best on a small number of large files. And HDFS doesn't currently
  	  support appends, making it difficult to keep the distributed copy fresh.
  	  </p>
  	  <p>
  	  Chukwa aims to provide a flexible and powerful platform for distributed
  	  data collection and rapid data processing. Our goal is to produce a system
  	  that's usable today, but that can be modified to take advantage of newer
  	  storage technologies (HDFS appends, HBase, etc) as they mature. In order
  	  to maintain this flexibility, Chukwa is structured as a pipeline of
  	  collection and processing stages, with clean and narrow interfaces between
  	  stages. This will facilitate future innovation without breaking existing code.
  	  </p>
  	  <p>
  	  Chukwa has four primary components:
  	  </p>
  	  <ol>
  	  <li><strong>Agents</strong> that run on each machine and emit data.</li>
  	  <li><strong>Collectors</strong> that receive data from the agent and write
  	   it to stable storage.</li>
  	  <li><strong>MapReduce jobs</strong> for parsing and archiving the data.</li>
  	  <li><strong>HICC</strong>, the Hadoop Infrastructure Care Center; a web-portal
  	  style interface for displaying data.</li>
  	  </ol>
  	  
  	  <p>
  	  Below is a figure showing the Chukwa data pipeline, annotated with data
  	  dwell times at each stage. A more detailed figure is available at the end
  	  of this document.
  	  </p>
  	  <figure src="images/datapipeline.png" alt="A picture of the chukwa data pipeline"/>
	  </section>
	  
	  <section><title>Agents and Adaptors</title>
	  <p>
	  Chukwa agents do not collect some particular fixed set of data. Rather, they
	  support dynamically starting and stopping <em>Adaptors</em>, which small
	  dynamically-controllable modules that run inside the Agent process and are
	  responsible for the actual collection of data.
	  </p>
	  <p>
		These dynamically controllable data sources are called 
		adaptors, since they generally are wrapping some other data source, 
		such as a file or a Unix command-line tool.  The Chukwa <a href="agent.html">
		agent guide</a> includes an up-to-date list of available Adaptors.
	  </p>
	  <p>
	  Data sources need to be dynamically controllable because the particular data
	  being collected from a machine changes over time, and varies from machine 
	  to machine. For example, as Hadoop tasks start and stop, different log files
	  must be monitored. We might want to increase our collection rate if we 
	  detect anomalies.  And of course, it makes no sense to collect Hadoop 
	  metrics on an NFS server. 
	  </p>
	 </section>

	<section><title>Data Model</title>
	<p>Chukwa Adaptors emit data in <em>Chunks</em>. A Chunk is a sequence of bytes,
		 with some metadata. Several of these are set automatically by the Agent or 
		 Adaptors. Two of them require user intervention: <code>cluster name</code> and 
		 <code>datatype</code>.  Cluster name is specified in <code>conf/chukwa-agent-conf.xml</code>,
		  and is global to each Agent process.  Datatype describes the expected format 
		  of the data collected by an Adaptor instance, and it is specified when that 
		  instance is started. 
  </p>
		
		<p>The following table lists the Chunk metadata fields. 
		</p>
		
		<table>
		<tr><td>Field</td><td>Meaning</td><td>Source</td></tr>
		<tr><td>Source</td><td>Hostname where Chunk was generated</td><td>Automatic</td></tr>
		<tr><td>Cluster</td><td>Cluster host is associated with</td><td>Specified by user
		 in agent config</td></tr>
		<tr><td>Datatype</td><td>Format of output</td><td>Specified by user when Adaptor
		 started</td></tr>
		<tr><td>Sequence ID</td><td>Offset of Chunk in stream</td><td>Automatic, initial
		 offset specified when Adaptor started</td></tr>
		<tr><td>Name</td><td>Name of data source</td><td>Automatic, chosen by Adaptor</td></tr>
		</table>
		
		<p>Conceptually, each Adaptor emits a semi-infinite stream of bytes, numbered
		 starting from zero. The sequence ID specifies how many bytes each Adaptor has
		 sent, including the current chunk.  So if an adaptor emits a chunk containing
		 the first 100 bytes from a file, the sequenceID of that Chunk will be 100. 
		 And the second hundred bytes will have sequence ID 200.  This may seem a 
		 little peculiar, but it's actually the same way that TCP sequence numbers work.
		</p>
		
		<p>Adaptors need to take sequence ID as a parameter so that they can resume 
		correctly after a crash, and not send redundant data. When starting adaptors, 
		it's usually save to specify 0 as an ID, but it's sometimes useful to specify 
		something else. For instance, it lets you do things like only tail the second 
		half of a file. 
		</p>
		</section>
		
		<section><title>Collectors</title>
		<p>
		Rather than have each adaptor write directly to HDFS, data is sent across 
		the network to a <em>collector</em> process, that does the HDFS writes.  
		Each collector receives data from up to several hundred hosts, and writes all
		this data to a single <em>sink file</em>, which is a Hadoop sequence file of
		serialized Chunks. Periodically, collectors close their sink files, rename 
		them to mark them available for processing, and resume writing a new file.  
		Data is sent to collectors over HTTP.  
   </p>
   <p>
	 Collectors thus drastically reduce the number of HDFS files generated by Chukwa,
	 from one per machine or adaptor per unit time, to a handful per cluster.  
	 The decision to put collectors between data sources and the data store has 
	 other benefits. Collectors hide the details of the HDFS file system in use, 
	 such as its Hadoop version, from the adaptors.  This is a significant aid to 
	 configuration.  It is especially helpful when using Chukwa to monitor a 
	 development cluster running a different version of Hadoop or when using 
	 Chukwa to monitor a non-Hadoop cluster.  
		</p>
		<p>For more information on configuring collectors, see the 
		<a href="collector.html">Collector documentation</a>.</p>
		</section>
		
		<section><title>MapReduce processing</title>
		<p>
		Collectors write data in sequence files. This is convenient for rapidly
		getting data committed to stable storage. But it's less convenient for
		analysis or finding particular data items. As a result, Chukwa has a toolbox
		of MapReduce jobs for organizing and processing incoming data. </p>
		<p>
		These jobs come in two kinds: <em>Archiving</em> and <em>Demux</em>.
		The archiving jobs simply take Chunks from their input, and output new sequence
		files of Chunks, ordered and grouped. They do no parsing or modification of 
		the contents. (There are several different archiving jobs, that differ in
		precisely how they group the data.)
		</p>
		<p>  
		The Demux job, in contrast, take Chunks as input and parse them to produce
		ChukwaRecords, which are sets of key-value pairs.
		</p>
		<p>
		 For details on controlling this part of the pipeline, see the 
		 <a href="admin.html">Administration guide</a>. For details about the file
		 formats, and how to use the collected data, see the <a href="programming.html">
		 Programming guide</a>.
		</p>
		</section>
		
		<section><title>HICC</title>
		<p>
		HICC, the Hadoop Infrastructure Care Center is a web-portal
  	style interface for displaying data.  Data is fetched from a MySQL database,
  	which in turn is populated by a mapreduce job that runs on the collected data,
  	after Demux. The  <a href="admin.html">Administration guide</a> has details
  	on setting up HICC.
		</p>
		<p>And now, the full-size picture of Chukwa:</p>
		<figure  align="left" alt="Chukwa Components" src="images/components.gif" />
		
		</section>
  </body>
</document>